Cleaning a cheese grater is an absolute nightmare.
Yes it is, yes it is.
I'd rather grate my face.
Do you like to cook?
I love to cook.
I love to eat, I'm an extraordinary eater.
What's your favorite pizza place?
Did you ever go to that pizza place in Favignon when we were shooting?
I did not eat any gluten.
Oh, you didn't, did you?
No.
Are you back on gluten?
Nope.
No?
No.
Are we doing gluten free today?
We're gonna do a bait and switch.
Make a pizza that everyone here can enjoy, and then they have a gluten-free one for me.
Do you believe pineapple belongs on pizza?
For me, no.
I don't like sweet with my savory when it comes to pizza.
I like it.
I probably wouldn't order it, but I do like it.
Throw back a giant piece of prosciutto.
I remember my brother Sam nearly choked to death on some of that.
Is it good?
Yeah.
Really?
Mom put her hand in his mouth and like, it felt like he was pulling it forever out of his mouth.
That actually stressed me out.
I was gonna say.
I am Matt Damon and I am Tom Holland.
And we're here with the New York Times making pizza.
Honestly, it's like the moment someone tells me they're taking a picture of me, I forget how to just be a human being.
I'm like, we're gonna do more photos, so.
Oh, great.
There are a lot of different ways we could go.
This is just about every topping you can imagine.
I'm curious about the pasta.
You'd put pasta on pizza?
I'm gonna just see what happens naturally, I think.
My go-to as a struggling actor was one of those Domino's thin crust pepperoni, green pepper, and onion.
So I'm tempted to just do that.
Do you remember the first step?
Yeah.
He said, be generous.
Generous.
Liberal with the flour.
So you don't like cooking?
It's not that I don't like it.
It's just that I don't do it.
When I was a kid, my mother made my brother and I each cook one night a week.
Oh, that's fun.
I think that put me off it.
Oh, okay.
Well, there you go.
Who's usually the cook in your house?
My wife is not bad.
She's pretty good.
We, seamless is a wonderful option.
What's seamless?
It's a delivery service.
Oh, no way.
Wow, I've got a real thin bit in there.
Oh yeah, mine's bubbling in the middle.
That can't be good.
I don't wanna pretend like I cook all the time.
I also, in England we have Deliveroo, which I'm a frequent user of.
I am trying to cook more and more.
It's one of my things I'm trying to do this year.
I see one of these holes developing in my pizza.
I'm not happy about it.
See, I kinda have a fail safe, which is no matter what I do, mine's getting swapped out for a gluten free pizza, so.
Oh, oh.
Now you've got one of those, what were those things called, Arabees?
Those frisbees with the hole in the middle?
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
I just ruined mine.
I could wear it like a bib.
Right, I guess I'm gonna have to start again.
I didn't know till a couple years ago that I had that gluten intolerance.
I feel so much better without eating it, but it's a bummer.
Like, I love bread, I love pasta, I love pizza, but it's worth it, ultimately.
I thought you were just doing that for the movie.
I was.
I didn't realize.
I was, and then I. And then you realized how much better you felt?
Yeah.
Are you flipping it over and over?
I don't know what I'm doing, to be honest, but that looks horrendous.
Yeah, this is pretty bad.
There's people furious at our pizza making skills.
You've got to bring in a stuntman.
Have you ever worked in the food service industry?
I worked at a place called Croissant Du Jour with Ben Affleck.
It was like mostly baked goods, croissants, sandwiches, that kind of stuff.
I watched a pot wash in a pub.
That's what you guys call a dishwasher, pot washer?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Didn't last very long.
That feels better.
You gonna go cheese first, bro?
Yeah, cheese then toppings.
Yeah, yeah.
You want it to...
You ain't gonna put tomato on it?
Huh?
Don't you put, are you putting a sauce over it?
I guess you put the sauce, of course, then the cheese.
All right, hold on.
Yeah.
Hold on.
Thanks.
So I'm now one handed.
Hold on.
I got this.
There's spoons right here for you.
Oh, spoon schmoon.
I was thinking of like a piece of toast.
I was like, what do you make?
Can I assume you've never cooked with each other before?
No.
It's actually how we bonded before we started the movie.
This is what Nolan had us do.
I put way too much sauce on this.
Yeah, so did I, but I think that's going to work in our favor somehow.
I have faith.
Are you scooping it off and putting it back in?
I'm really hungry, and we have a long flight tonight.
We do have a long flight.
So I'm going to take this with me.
All right, I'm putting on some mozzarella cheese here.
Yeah.
Just a lot of dust.
And then that looks like kind of a sharp cheddar, which I'm not afraid to double that up a little bit.
Are you a fan of pre-grated cheese?
I am when it comes to taco night, because that is a pain in the ass.
Yeah, because we don't really do that in the UK.
Like in the UK, you buy like a block of cheese.
And grate it, yeah.
And you grate it yourself.
But when I came to America the first time, I was like, that is so handy.
And also, cleaning a cheese grater is an absolute nightmare.
Yes, it is.
I'd rather grate my face.
When we were filming the movie, we shot in this place called Favagnana.
It's a really gorgeous island just off the coast of Sicily.
And there was this great pizzeria there.
I ate there every single night that we were in Favagnana.
And they made this fiery pepperoni pizza.
Fortunately, I was not cutting out gluten while I was making that movie.
And I ate it every single night.
But it was spicy, so I'm gonna have to add something a little spicier than...
It's got a little kick to it.
Got some good.
Some little secondary.
Jon Bernthal and I did hot ones the other day.
Oh yeah, man.
I mean, I fully vomited on camera.
On camera?
Full time, like I'm standing there with laughing, having a good time.
I can't even, didn't I tell you when I did it, I threw up?
Oh, did you?
Off camera, but yeah.
Oh, mate.
And it was also pure milk.
Oh, oh, because you.
Because I'd been nailing the milk.
I literally.
And the other time I was like, we're not here to talk about hot ones.
If you were away from home for 20 years, what's the first thing you'd eat?
Well, it depends on where I was away from home, what kind of food they had available there.
So the question would really be what I miss the most at home.
I was on an Odyssey.
So I'm on a boat, I'm eating fish.
I'd probably eat a good steak when I got home.
My brother Sam makes this dish called a chicken veronique, which is like a shredded chicken in a creamy sauce.
And then he like hand peels green grapes and roasts them.
And then he serves it on like a d'auphinoise potato bottom.
That sounds fantastic.
Unbelievable.
That's what I would have.
Odysseus returns home in disguise after 20 years and subtly signaled to his loved ones his true identity.
If you had to do this, how would your loved ones know it was actually you?
Like one of my daughters, just whenever I see her, she goes, you know, hey, chat, how you doing?
I go, hey, chat.
So I could walk by her and just say, hey, chat, and she'd know who I was.
I'd probably just go see my mom.
You know, I've been seeing those videos recently.
Have you seen them?
They like get an NFL team to sit in an auditorium and then they get all the moms to stand up at the front and turn their back
to the room.
And the kids have to like call their mom in a funny voice.
And it's like 99% of the time, the mom will turn around when it's their son.
Oh, really?
It actually kind of amazing.
So I probably just go see my mom and she would know immediately.
You must have the most wholesome Instagram feed of anybody.
If you were to show each other around your hometowns, where's the first place you'd eat?
Oh boy, I wonder if all of them exist anywhere.
There's a place in Central Square, Cambridge, called the Middle East Cafe, which is great.
Joseph and Nabil, shout out to those guys.
They own it, they've been there forever.
And That's a great spot.
I would take them there.
Yeah.
There's a pub in Kingston called The Coconut.
It's a Thai restaurant.
You can bring your dogs there.
Oh, nice.
And people just let their dogs off, so it becomes like a dog free for all.
Wally is the lady that runs the pub, and it's like a bit of a family favorite of ours.
Are we gonna cook these now?
Oh wait, there's garlic.
Let's throw some garlic on here.
Oh, some little garlic crisps.
Throw some garlic crisps on there.
We make the flight even more enjoyable.
I put one solitary piece of pineapple in the middle of mine, so that you know it's yours.
Yeah.
That's not working at all.
Oh wait, it's stuck.
Can somebody just look at that?
You gotta get a shot of that.
Everything came off the pizza.
That has become now very like a pizza you'd get in a box.
Yes.
At a 7-Eleven is what that has become very quickly.
Without a doubt.
Oh, you've lost every...
I've lost everything from the top.
You've got one piece of pepper left.
Oh my God.
Right, I'm ready.
Catastrophe.
I'm going at the bottom.
Wow, it is hot in there.
Oh, like a pro!
Ladies and gentlemen.
All right, quick run.
I think my dough was so wet it just absorbed everything.
Wow.
All right, there you go, that is a hot mess.
Woo!
What do you mean by feed it?
You have to keep it alive by continuing to give it water and flour.
I can see all the people too who've fed it so far at the kitchen.
Anyone we know?
Look at this.
You should.
Oh, Jake and Maggie Gyllenhaal.
I bet they're good cooks.
Yeah.
I've been to one of Jake's Sunday dinners.
You wanna go flour or water?
I'll go water, pal.
I hope you become the sourest of sourdough starters.
You can do it.
Yeah?
You can start stirring.
No, I was talking about the sourdough.
We believe in you.
Yeah.
We want you to grow and feed so many people, make so many people happy.
Just persevere.
Persevere.
Every time you get fed, just gobble it up.
I love the way you're holding me.
I know.
I'm Tom Holland, and I sell bread.
Here we go.
If the cast of The Odyssey owned a restaurant, what would everyone's role be?
We'd have to put Chris on the door.
Well, I might put you as the maitre d'.
Yeah?
Yeah, I would want you to be the face of the restaurant.
Welcoming people in.
Welcome.
Yeah.
Clearly I'd be washing dishes because I would not be cooking.
But you could run the business though.
Imagine like you and Ben, you could run.
He's not in the Odyssey.
I'm not in the Odyssey, but I could call him for advice.
Exactly.
Let's see, where would you put Bernthal?
If it were in a bad neighborhood, you'd want Bernthal at the door.
Yeah, for sure.
That's absolutely right.
Chris maybe gives me the vibes that he would be a good baker for some reason.
Ah, so you're putting them on dessert?
Yeah.
All right, all right.
I like it.
Whoa, Annie, where do we put Annie?
Is she into cooking?
I think she is.
I think she might be our chef.
She could be head chef.
Yeah.
A bartender.
Oh, Charlize.
Charlize would be a good bartender.
I, a good Charlie the bar.
Hamesh would be on dishes with me.
Zendaya.
Oh, our pizzas are burning.
Hot pizza, that's beautiful.
Look at that.
And the too much sauce only resulted in a little puddle in the middle, but that's fine.
It's a little made a little soup.
I was stuck at the end, huh?
All right, that looks sad.
That looks more like a calzone.
How do you feel about them, though?
Yeah, I'm a little disappointed with how mine crisped up.
You know, like the edges have gone really dark, but I'm kind of lacking some of that crispiness in the pepperoni.
But maybe that's because I basically made a soup.
Now, my question is, would you like some of my gluten-free pizza?
Because it looks beautiful.
I was actually expecting you to do much better than this.
I thought I was going to nail it.
Your gluten-free pizza, that looks fantastic.
That looks like the pizza from the early 90s that I would get from Domino's.
If you were a food dish, what would you be, and can you answer for each other?
I would.
Say you're a fillet meat.
A fillet meat, I can't remember the word.
My brain has gone blank.
A fillet mignon, that's what I'm trying to say.
Or a T-bone steak.
I'd say prime rib.
Like fantastic cut, delivers on its promise.
You can count on it, Tom Holland.
I think you'd be this kind of meat.
Here's the kind of steak you'd be.
Here we go.
Oh, I got a nice crunch throughout.
That's good.
I always say to myself, I should buy a pizza cutter.
Not that I make pizza at home, but where I get my pizza from in London, and if I get it delivered, they don't cut the pizza.
They don't cut it all the way?
They don't cut it at all.
And every time I'm like, just go out and buy a pizza cut.
You're going eight pieces, huh?
Can I have this?
Yeah, nice.
I'm actually chuffed.
That's happy in English.
Yeah.
Now that is a good-looking pizza.
That ain't too bad.
No, I mean this.
So when I was making my pizza, what I was trying to do was go with a thinner crust.
I like that, man.
Yeah.
Oh, this looks great.
Oh, it's so good.
How is it?
Hot.
Yeah, it's actually really tasty.
This is delicious, yeah.
Does it taste like the one you're trying to recreate?
No.
That place in Fabiana is probably one of the best pizzas I've ever had.
Right.
Yeah.
When we shot in Fabiana.
That is so hot.
Fabiana is this little town, but we got there off season.
And the people in the town opened up their restaurants and opened basically the town up because it's so small and our crew is so big.
That we kind of had to run into town for the first few weeks.
It was really lovely.
It was awesome.
Does anyone want a piece?
You didn't seem very convinced, Sam.
Your face was a little bit like, nah, we'll let someone else make the pizza.
Thank you to the New York Times.
Sorry about this pizza to whoever's going to eat it.
But this was a lot of fun.
And the movie, The Odyssey, comes out on July 17.
You.